所以，这个爱尔兰男人，敲了这个女人的门说，有任何工作吗？
So, this Irish guy, knocks on this lady's door and says, ya know, ya got any...any work for me?
她说，嗯，你知道，事实上，你可以帮我刷门廊的油漆
And she say, Um... well, ya know, as a matter of fact, ya... ya can paint the porch.
大概两小时后，那个男人回来说
About two hours later the guy comes back and says,
「我做完了，女士，只是顺便跟你说，那不是保时捷，是BMW」
(保时捷跟门廊的发音类似)
"I'm finished, Ma'am, but just for your information it's not a Porch, it's a BMW."
圣人文森特
好吧，浑蛋，醒醒
Okay, asshole, giddy up!
喔，天啊，我感觉到婴儿在踢，快摸摸看
Oh, my God, feel this, baby's kicking, feel, touch it.
不，不是我的胸，是这裡
No, not my boob, here.
抱歉我们吵醒你了
Sorry we woke you up.
就是他，这家伙吵醒你
It was him, this asshole.
- 这是怎样？  - 我现在手头有点紧
- What's this? - I'm a little tight right now.
我不接受分期付款，我不是杰西潘尼百货公司
My shit is not layaway, I'm not J.C. Penny.
- 你知道我喜欢小婴儿  - 不，不要想跟以前一样，文森
- You know I'm good for it. - No, don't make like before, Vin.
只有怪胎才喜欢孕妇，我们得替产假预先存钱
Only few freaks like the belly, We have to save for maternity leave.
- 嘿，我喜欢孕妇，好吗？  - 我们下星期二见
- Hey, I like the belly, okay? - I'll see you next Tuesday.
你要加小费，两倍小费
Extras when you do, okay... double.
这裡说明已经冻结了
This one here says the line's frozen.
没错，这些反向抵押贷款，你只能借
Yes, we these reverse mortgages, you can only borrow
你拥有这间房子的产权的百分比
a percentage of the equity you have in the house.
这叫做货款价值
That's call the loan to value.
现在，由于你过去八年，每个月从我们这边获得的
But, now, since you've been getting monthly payments from us for the last...
贷款，你已经达到付款上限
eight years, you've reached the cash out limit.
就是我刚刚跟你说的货款价值
That's that loan to value thing I just mentioned.
- 这房子价值....   - 过去价值...
- The house it worth... - It WAS worth...
不管怎样都是以前的事
whatever it WAS worth.
我需要这笔钱
I need that money.
抱歉，麦肯纳先生，我真的爱莫能助...
I'm sorry, Mr. McKenna, there really nothing I can do...
- 就是这样  - 就是这样？
- It is what it is. - It is what it is?
现在每个人都说这句话，你知道这什麽意思吗？
Now everyone's saying that now, you know what it means?
你完蛋了，而且你就只能完蛋
You're screwed and you shall remain screwed.
我要关闭这个帐户
I wanna close this account.
我很遗憾，先生，我可以问为什麽吗？
So sorry to hear that, Sir, may I ask why?
小姐，你只是一个小齿轮，努力过著像我们一样悲惨
Lady, you're just a spoke on a wheel, tryin' to make a livin' like the rest of us schmucks.
我一点也不想跟你说为什麽，只要...
I do NOT want to tell you to go fuck yourself so, let's...
我要关闭帐户，好吗，就这样，拜託你
I'm closin' it, okay, let's just leave it at that, please.
好的
Okay.
122元又14分
One hundred twelve dollars and fourteen cents.
- 请给我小钞  - 不，先生，那是你透支的金额
- I'd like small bills. - No, Sir, you're overdrawn that much.
这是什麽意思？
What does THAT mean?
你提走的钱比你的帐户裡还要多
You took out more money that you actually have in your account.
这是零元，而你比零元还低
Here's zero, you went below zero.
- 所以我没办法关闭帐户？  - 可以，只要你先让透支归零
- So I CAN'T close this account? - You CAN, once you get it back to zero.
嘿，你过的还好吗？文森
Hey, you takin' care of yourself, Vince?
没错，花眼睛，我现在在做有氧运动，你看不出来吗？
Yeah, Flurry Eyes, I'm doin' aerobics, can't you tell?
我在做珍芳达式的健身，一、二、三，伸展
I'm doin' the Jane Fonda workout. 1, 2, 3 and stretch.
珍还是很漂亮
Jane is still lookin' good.
罗杰，你能不能倒一杯
Roger, is there any chance you could ever make one of
够烈的酒给某个不是你妹的人？
these that's strong enough for someone that's not... your sister?
- 要不要暂停一下？  - 暂停啥？
- Why don't we give it a break, for a minute. - Give what a break?
倒酒给你
The liquor.
- 你不打算给我倒酒？  - 不要这样，我在注意你
- You're not gonna serve me? - Don't be like that, I'm watchin' out for you here.
你在注意我？你整天替这些什麽都不知道的人灌毒
You watchin' out for me? You serve poison all day to all these people who don't know no better?
让他们死掉你活著？现在你又在注意我了？
So they can die while they're livin'? And you're watchin' out for me?
你这白痴
You're full.
好极了
Nice.
起来了，老兄
Get up, man.
闭嘴，有人在睡觉欸
Shut up! People are sleeping!
该死
God damn.
嘿，怎麽一回事？
Hey! What's goin' on?
你们不会说英文吗？
You habla English?
- 我们会说英文，先生  - 那你们在做啥？
- Yes, we speak English, Señor. - Then what the hell you doing here?
那是我的树，你们两个浑蛋撞坏...我的篱笆
That's MY tree, you assholes hit... and my fence.
还有我的车
My damn car.
- 你们会说英文吗？  - 待在车上
- Do you speak English? - Stay here.
是的，先生
Yes, Señor.
- 我要报警  - 没问题吧
- I'm calling the cops. - Is everybody okay?
- 你要干嘛？  - 我叫玛姬，我是你的新邻居
- What do you want? - I'm Maggie, I'm your new neighbor.
那又怎样？
So?
- 嗯，我们正要搬进来  - 我看的出来
- Well, we're moving in. - I can see that?
这两个王八蛋是你的人吗？
Are these dip-shits with you?
没错，他们是搬家公司的人
Yes, they're the men I hired from the moving company.
- 喔，天啊  - 喔，天啊，不，糟的一蹋糊涂
- Oh, boy. - Oh, boy. no, oh, shit's more like it.
这个篱笆二十年历史了，这台车三十年，这株树比我还老
This fence is 20 years old, the car's 30, the tree is older than I am.
嗯，我很抱歉，我不确定...我，这不是我想要打招呼的方式...
Well, I'm sorry, I'm not sure... well, I'm... this is not how I wanted to meet either...
是你们干的吗？
Did you do this?
当然是他们干的，你是白痴吗，看看犯罪现场
Of course they did it, what are you, stupid, look at the crime scene.
你不需要这麽不礼貌
You don't have to be rude to me.
我才刚搬到这裡，我请人搬家，然后意外发生
I'm just trying to move in here, I hired these guys to do it, and accidents happen.
- 哼，这台车是骨董了，小姐，价值不少钱  - 我会解决
- Well, the car's an antique, missy, it's worth a lot. - And I'll take care of it.
你？你连钱都没有，怎样，我是说，不要介意，但你看起来一点钱也没有
You? You don't got no money, what, I mean, no offense, but you just don't look like you do.
好吗，我也确定拉丁仔跟那家伙也没有钱
Okay, I'm sure Chico and the man here are off the books.
不，我会告搬家公司
No, I will sue the moving company.
你可以处理篱笆跟树
You can buck-up for the fence... and the tree.
好吧
Fine.
一群智障
Toodles.
- 这就是我们的新邻居？  - 没错
- Is that our new a neighbor? - Yep.
看样子要过得很痛苦了
It's gonna be a long life.
「好吧，说说这树，她儘可能地挺起身子」
"Well, said the tree.", she straightened herself up as much as much as she could"
「这树桩适合坐下休息」
"well, now the stump is good for sitting and resting."
「来吧，男孩，坐下，坐下休息」那男孩坐下，而树感到开心
"Come, boy, sit down, sit down and rest." And the boy did and the tree was happy.
- 天啊，真无聊  - 不，这不会...
- God, that's depressing. - No, it's not...
树做出了奉献，能够给予一切
The tree was made to give, so, to be able to give everything
直到一无所有，是他最好的人生
and have nothing left is the best life she could ever have.
嗯，你爸一定也认为我是株树
Well, your father must think I'm a tree.
- 你怎麽会想到...   - 没事，没事
- How do you think... - Nothin', nothin'.
你想到正面就是好事，来吧，上床吧
It's good ya think good things. C'mon, get in there.
- 明天很重要  - 嗯，我知道，上学第一天
- Big day tomorrow. - Yeah, I know, first day.
嗯，我也是，而且我不能迟到
Yeah, for me, too and I can't be late.
- 好吗，只剩你跟我了  - 我知道
- All right, it's just you and me now. - I know.
设好闹钟确保我不会睡过头
Set the alarm and make sure I don't oversleep.
晚安
Good night.
好了，给你，我替你弄了花生三明治跟香蕉
All right, here, I made you peanut butter and banana.
谢谢，妈
Thanks, Mom.
好，你确定有带零用钱跟钥匙吗？
Okay, do you have your snack money in your pocket and your keys?
有
Yep!
- 手机呢？  - 嗯
- You got your phone? - Uh-huh.
- 地图？  - 嗯，手机裡有
- Map? - Yep, on the phone.
- 好吧，你几点放学？  - 2:45
- Okay, what time you get out? - 2:45.
好，我要你直接回家然后就写作业
All right, I want you to come straight home and start your homework and
我大概要再过几个小时才会回家
I'll be home a couple of hours after that.
等等，妈，你没有要接我吗？
Wait, Ma, you're not gonna pick me up or anything?
我挡到公车了，我可不想接到罚单，奥利佛，再见，乖一点
I'm in the bus lane, I'm not gonna get another ticket, Oliver... bye... be good.
圣派翠克小学
好吧，有点吵，有点吵，安静下来，安静下来
Okay, a little loud, a little loud, settle down, settle down, settle down.
我知道你们很难控制自己，尤其你们还这麽小又喝了一堆果汁
I know it's hard to contain yourselves when you're so, so young and full of sugar juice.
但我们一定要专心在课业上，要不然呢，我们会笨死，没错
But we must concentrate on our studies or we will what? We will die dumb, yes, we will.
愚笨在天堂不是好事
And dumbness does not play well in Heaven.
这位是奥利佛，奥利佛在学期中加入圣派翠克
This is Oliver, Oliver is joining us mid-stream here at St. Patrick.
- 我们非常开心迎接他，对吧  - 欢迎来到圣派翠克小学，奥利佛
- And we are very happy to have him, are we not? - Welcome to St. Patrick, Oliver.
非常有同学爱，谢谢各位，你感觉到了，你感觉到了对吗？
That's genuine caring, thank you, I think. You feel touched, right? You feel touched by that?
也许你可以带领大家做晨祷感谢同学
Maybe as a thank you, you can lead us all in morning prayer.
- 我想....我是犹太人   - 好吧，知道了
- I think... I think I'm Jewish. - Okay, good to know.
- 奥利佛认为他是犹太人  - 我也是
- Oliver thinks he's Jewish. - So am I.
- 我是佛教徒  - 根本就没有神
- I'm Buddhist. - There is no God.
你了解了吧，这裡我们接受全世界所有宗教，奥利佛
Yeah, you get the idea, we celebrate all the religions of the world in this room, Oliver.
我是天主教徒，也是最好的宗教，真的，因为我们的规矩最多
I'm a Catholic, which is the best of all the religions, really, because we have the most rules.
制服也最好看
And the best clothes.
我们之中，有佛教徒，不可知论者，浸信会教徒
But among us, there's also a Buddhist, agnostic, we have a Baptist,
我们也有「我不知道」教，似乎是世界上成长最快的宗教
and we have a I-Don't-Know, which seems to be the fastest growing religion in the world.
现在我们有「我想我是犹太人」教，这裡最新的一位，奥利佛，感谢你
And now we have I-Think-I'm-Jewish. which is a new one for the class, Oliver, so thanks for that.
但这不妨碍你替我们做晨祷
But it does not preclude you from giving us a morning prayer.
大家低头祷告
Let us bow our heads and pray.
- 亲爱的...  - 神...之类的
- Dear... - "God"... et cetera.
亲爱的神，谢谢你？
Dear God, thank you?
阿门
Amen.
- 阿门  - 阿门，阿门，谢谢神
- Amen. - Amen, amen, thanks be to God.
好了，开始上课
All right, stirring stuff.
现在，奥利佛，你自己找位置坐，其他人
Well, now, Oliver, go grab yourself a seat, and everybody else,
把课本拿出来上第十二课
let's dust off those textbooks and go to chapter 12.
第十二课，天主教圣人
Now, Chapter 12, Catholic saints.
贝蒙园马场
好了，我在这
All right, I'm here.
我在这，我准备好了，我可以，上吧，加油
I'm here, I'm ready, I'm able, let's get this, come on.
快啊，跑起来，快
Come on! Dig in! Come on.
快啊
Come on!
这麽一次
One time!
就这麽该死的一次
One damn time!
你真是小浑蛋
You son of a bitch.
我不知道为什麽你生气，文尼
I don't know why you get so pissy, Vinny.
你总是...看起来很平静的样子
You always lose... it seems like you'd be comfortable by now.
是啊，难熬的一天
Yeah, tough day.
你还真自动
Help yourself.
我很渴而且你欠我前，文尼
I'm thirsty and you owe me money, Vinny.
- 我现在有问题要处理  - 你知道我不是唯一经营者
- Got a situation I'm workin' out. - You know I'm not the sole proprietor here.
- 我还要面对其他人  - 再给我一点时间，就这样
- I've got other people to answer to. - Just need a little time, that's all.
- 那我要怎麽跟其他人说  - 一个月
- So, what do I tell them? - A month.
这会害我们分裂，改成两个星期吧
We'll split the difference, make it two weeks.
小心
Watch out!
好了，做几下？
All right, how many?
时间到
And it's TIME.
你可以放手了
You can let go now.
你之前的学校有体育课吧？
Did they have physical education in the last school you went to?
有
Yes.
- 你有上吗？  - 有，老师
- Did you take it. - Yes, Sir.
- 看看谁来了  - 强壮哥
- Look who it is. - There's the strong man.
- 我想我是犹太人  - 我叫奥利佛
- "I think I'm Jewish." - My name's Oliver, by the way.
「我叫奥利佛」你这小砸碎，你从哪裡来的啊
"My name's Oliver." You little turd, where did you come from anyway, huh?
各位，你们听到钟声了吗？这表示要去上课了，快点，移动
Hello! Did you guys hear the bell? That means to move, go to class, come on, let's go.
连一个仰卧起坐都做不到
Can't even do a sit-up.
- 你需要地图吗？  - 不用
- You need a map? - No, Sir.
那你最好有多馀的时间，要不然你就会迟到了，快移动
Well, you better double-time it, or you're gonna be late, let's go.
该死
Shit.
短裤真好看
Nice shorts.
先生
Sir.
- 带我走，上帝，不要玩我  - 是我，先生
- Take me, God, don't play with me. - It's me, Sir.
- 嗯，怎麽了？  - 可不可以借你的电话
- Yeah! What? - I was wondering if I could use your phone?
- 电话？  - 对
- My phone? - Yes.
- 我家的？  - 是的，先生
- In my house? - Yes, Sir.
我要打给我妈，我被关在我家外面，因为体育课的同学
I need to call my mom, I'm locked out of the house 'cause these guys in gym class
把我的钥匙我的电话拿走，所以我进不去...他们还拿走我的手表...
took my keys and my phone, and I can't get in... they also stole my watch...
我不需要厅全部的故事，好吗
I don't need to hear the whole story, okay?
只淮打一通
One call!
海，我是麦姬，现在没办法接电话，请留言
Hi, it's Maggie, can't take your call right now, please leave a message.
嘿，妈，我弄丢家裡的钥匙，还有钱包跟手机，
Hey, Mom, I lost my keys for the house, and my wallet and my phone, and
我在隔壁老头的家
I'm at the old guy's next door.
- 先生，你叫什麽名字？  - 文森特，老头
- Sir, what's your name? - Vincent, The Old Guy.
文森特，老头
Vincent, The Old Guy.
很不友善
The Mean One.
- 你叫甚麽名字？  - 奥利佛，先生
- What's your name? - It's Oliver, Sir.
你可以在学校穿短裤吗？
They let you wear those shorts to school?
- 这故事很长  - 我确定
- It's a long story, Sir. - I'm sure it is.
- 嗯？  - 海，我是玛姬
- Yeah? - Hi, this is Maggie.
- 奥利佛的妈  - 你的孩子在这
- Oliver's mom. - You're kid's here.
- 嗯，我知道，我收到留言，我希望他没事  - 怎样叫没事？
- Yeah, I know, I got his message, I hope that's all right. - Is what all right?
- 就是他待在你那  - 待在我这？是怎样，什麽意思？
- That he stays there. - Stays here? Like what "stays here."?
我在工作，这裡又多了三四个病人，我可能还要几个小时才能离开，这裡很忙
I'm at work, I got 3 or 4 more cases, and I'm not gonna be home for a few hours, so I'm kind of in a jam here.
你要我当保母？
You want me to babysit?
嗯，这...他又不是小婴儿，我是说，他应该
Well, it's not... it's not like he's a baby, I mean, he's just probably
只会安静地写作业，他很随和
gonna sit quietly and do his homework, he's... he's really easy.
先生，有...
Sir, is that...
- 你要付多少钱？  - 什麽？
- How much you payin'? - What?
你要我当保母...我可不是做慈善事业
You want me to babysit... I'm not a philanthropy.
- 一个小时十元？  - 12元
- Ten dollars an hour? - Twelve!
- 好吧，一小时12元，我可以跟他讲话吗？  - 找你的
- Okay, 12 dollars an hour, can I talk to him? - It's for you.
- 牠不太喜欢其他人   - 我对动物很有一套，先生
- He doesn't like many people. - I'm good with animals, Sir.
嗯，牠不喜欢那种自称对动物有一套的人
Yeah, he doesn't usually like people who say they're good with animals.
你没看过阿伯与卡斯通？(美国喜剧演员团体)
You never seen Abbott and Costello?
- 没有，先生，他们很老了吗？  - 不，他们死了
- No, Sir, are they old? - No, they're dead.
最老就是这样
That's the oldest you can be.
或是最年轻....死亡后时间就停止了
Or the youngest... time freezes when you're dead.
- 你从哪裡学到这个？  - 一本书上
- Where did you learn that? - A book.
- 哪本书？- 儿童书，先生
- What book? - A kid's book, Sir.
我敢说你不知道
I doubt you'd know it.
晚餐时间了，你饿了吗？
It's dinnertime, you hungry or somethin'?
- 有一点，先生  - 我想想看
- A little, Sir. - That's figures.
你可以吃寿司
You're gettin' sushi.
- 大概是你妈  - 大概吧，先生
- It's probably your mother. - Probably, Sir.
- 不用起来了  - 好哇
- Don't get up. - Okay.
海，我...
Hi, I...
海，文森特
Hi... Vincent.
- 是我  - 我是玛姬...我...
- Yep. - Maggie... I...
感谢你照顾他，你知道，那是新工作我又失去....
Thank you for watching him, ya know, a new job and I've lost...
- 我不需要听那麽多  - 好吧
- I don't need to hear the whole story. - Okay.
喔，对了
Oh, here.
...3小时，12元...
...at 3 hours at 12...
- 36块  - 嗯，我知道
- Thirty-six. - Yeah, yeah, I know that.
- 我有两张二十元   - 我没有零钱
- I got two twenties. - I don't have change, of course.
好吧
That's fine.
你怎麽没有找人照顾你小孩
How come you don't have anyone to watch this kid after school?
- 我们刚搬过来  - 父亲在哪？
- We just moved in. - Where's the father?
我们在大学任是，后来...他遇见了别人....
We met in college and it turned out that... he had been seeing...
不需要说这麽说，你要付我篱笆的钱吗？
No need to tell it, then. You gonna pay for my fence?
- 嗯，我...对，我说过我会....   - 还有树
- Yeah, I... yes... I said I was going... - And my tree?
我不知道怎麽算树枝的钱
I'm not sure how... I can pay for a branch.
每个东西都有价格，你是大人了，你应该知道这点
Everything has a price, you're an adult, you should know that.
- 好吧，你跟我说   - 我可以替你照护小孩，几个钟头
- All right, let me know. - I can watch the kid after school... a few hours.
价格一样，可以改成11元一个小时，点心费你出
Same price, I can do eleven dollars an hour, you pay the snacks.
你孩子吃了我最后一罐沙丁鱼罐头
Your kid ate my last can of sardines.
真的吗？
Really?
你可以闻闻他的嘴
You can smell his breath.
- 我以为你不是在文森特家吃过了  - 我们吃了寿司
- I thought you ate at Vincent's house. - We had sushi.
- 你吃了寿司？   - 其实是沙丁鱼，他宣称是寿司
- You had sushi? - Well, sardines, he calls it sushi.
我不想伤害他
Didn't want to hurt his feelings.
- 所以你喜欢他吗？  - 他很有趣
- So, you like him? - He's interesting.
- 他有点酷，特别是发牢骚的时候  - 嗯，的确是他的擅长
- He's sorta cool, in a grouchy sort of way. - Well, that he is.
他有一头很有趣的猫...菲力
He has a cool cat though... Felix.
你知道，他主动说要照顾你
You know, he offered to watch you after school.
- 是吗？  - 这很糟，对吧
- He did? - It's a horrible idea, right?
嗯，他就住在隔壁，你也找不到更近的了
Well, he lives right next door, you can't get closer than that.
嗯，我的确有想过，这样就不用花时间再找
Yeah, I... I had thought about that, you know, save me from having to find a babysitter.
你会在家吧？
You will be home though, right?
嗯，我得离家工作，有时候会晚一点
Yeah I'm away from home, but sometimes late, you know,
我是唯一有工作的人，你爸一点用也没有
I'm the one that has to work now, your father's not helping.
我不知道他要干嘛，你的学校也不便宜
I don't know if he's ever going to, your school's not exactly cheap.
我想他这麽老了也干不了坏事，或是不够老干不了，如果你懂我的意思的话
I guess he's too old to be dangerous, not too old to be too dangerous, either, if you know what I mean.
- 真是蠢地方   - 谁又惹怒你了？
- Stupid place. - Who pissed in your Cheerios?
- 我不能再跳舞了  - 嗯，真是大新闻
- Can't dance no more. - Well, that's a surprise.
我们需要钱，文森
We need the money, Vin.
- 慈悲的品质突然降低了  - 我应该告那些浑蛋
- The quality of mercy is suddenly strained. - I should sue these assholes.
用什麽罪名，歧视怀孕妇女，对吗？
What the word? Discrimination against pregnant woman, yes?
我想你有很好的机会告赢
I think ya got a real good case.
这个大肚子害我少赚多少钱
This stupid bump is costing me much money.
- 他很快就会让你花更多  - 不是他
- He's gonna cost you a lot more pretty soon. - It's not he.
- 还是女儿？  - 我怎麽会知道？
- It's a she? - How I know this?
- 你以为我是灵媒吗？  - 不，你不是
- I look like psychic to you? - No, you don't.
- 但现在有机器  - 是，我知道有机器
- But they have technology. - Yeah, I know what they have.
也许我可以打电话给脱衣舞老板给我健保卡让我去做超音波
But, maybe I call stripper employer and ask them to fax insurance card to pay ultrasound?
是吗？
Nyet?
我的问题是：什麽才是圣人
So, I suppose the question is: What is a saint?
什麽才是圣人，有人知道圣人是什麽吗？我不认为你知道，喔，瑞秋
What is a saint, anybody know what a saint is? I don't think they do... oh, Rachele.
展现神圣行为的人
Individuals who display and act out with exceptional holiness.
非常好，谢谢你瑞秋，有人可以讲圣人的名字吗？
That's pretty perfect, thank you Rachele. Who can name a saint?
- 耶利米  - 圣犹达
- Jeremiah. - St. Jude.
- 圣犹达，没错，圣犹达知名的事蹟有什麽？  - 我想他开了一家医院，是吗？
- St. Jude, yes, and what is St. Jude known for? - I think he has a hospital, right?
还有高尔夫球赛，就这样，好吧
And the golf tournament, right? That's it? Okay.
有人知道现代的圣人吗？
Anyone know any modern-day saints?
- 布莉琪   - 泰瑞莎修女
- Bridgette. - Mother Teresa.
泰瑞莎修女，没错，现代知名的圣人，
Mother Teresa, yes, the big M.T. of the Modern Day Saints, so...
所谓的圣人，就是承诺替其他人奉献的人
A saint is a human being we celebrate for their commitment and dedication to other human beings,
他们努力工作，牺牲，为了让世界更美好
for the sacrifices that they make, for their hard work in making the world a better place
这些在我们身边，以及追随这些圣人的人
for those around us and for those who will follow them.
晚安
Good night.
- 玛姬布朗？  - 海
- Maggie Bronstein? - Hi.
罗宾请病假，后面又来了六个病人
Robin called in sick, got six cases backed up.
嗯，我得回家接我儿子
Yeah, I have to go pick up my son, though.
抱歉，我不能在没有人接班的情况下让你下班，医院政策
Sorry, I can't let you clock-out without the shift being covered... hospital policy.
来啊，懦夫，你要卖我什麽
Come on, coward, try to sell me somethin'.
你这邪恶女巫，我准备听你说完屁话然后就挂电话
You evil witch, I'm gonna listen to your whole God damned spiel, and then I'm gonna hang up.
- 文森特，我是玛姬  - 玛姬？真是好事
- Vincent, it's Maggie. - Maggie? That's a good one.
你是加尔各答的玛姬还是新德里的玛姬？
Is it Maggie from Calcutta or is it Maggie from New Delhi?
不，我是你的邻居玛姬
No, it's your neighbor, Maggie.
你想干嘛？
What the hell you want?
走吧！
Let's go!
- 你最好繫上安全带  - 你没有繫啊
- You better buckle-up. - You're not buckled.
我的生命安全是我的问题
My life is my problem.
- 直接回家吗？  - 不是
- This is the way home? - No.
- 嘿，我们说好一些SOP  - 我不知道SOP是什麽意思，先生
- Hey, let's lay down some S.O.P. - I don't know what S.O.P. means, Sir.
标准作业程序
Standard Operating Procedure.
我去哪你就去哪，我说什麽你就照做，在这段时间把作业做完
You go where I go, you do what I say, get your homework done somewhere along the way,
最重要的是，不淮吵我，要是有人吵我我会很不爽
But most importantly, you DON'T annoy me, I'm not happy when I'm annoyed.
现在有人吵你吗？
Are you annoyed right now?
- 并没有  - 真的吗？
- Not particularly. - Really?
给你一毛钱，打电话给你妈，跟他说你现在很安全
Here's a dime, call your mom, tell her you're wearing your seatbelt.
打电话不只一毛钱
It costs more than a dime.
- 什麽时候开始的？  - 我出生之前就这样了
- Since when? - Since before I was born.
这国家都在搞什麽鬼
What is this country comin' to?
给你，要是还不够，就打对方付费电话
Here, if the cost's more than that, call collect.
嘿，快看，是这砸碎，你住在这附近？
Hey! Look! It's dipshit. You live in this neighborhood?
我差点因为你被留校察看，王八蛋
I'll probably got detention because of you, asshole.
你会被留校察看是因为你拿走我的东西
You probably got detention because you took my stuff.
你怎麽知道是我拿的，打小报告
How do you know I took it, you NARC!
他被打了一巴掌
He's got flat feet.
闭嘴
Shut up!
弄倒他了
Ya got him.
砸碎，要是老师问你，你最好一句话都别说，知道了吗
Dipshit, you make some of the teachers ask you what happened, you don't say anything, you got it?
- 放开我  - 不，我才不管
- Get off me. - No! I don't care!
- 你可以回家哭著找嬷嬷了  - 你们几个小浑蛋在干嘛？
- So, you can go cry to your mommy. - What are you shit-heels doin'?
- 你是罗伯特奥兹吗？  - 不是，先生
- Is that you Robert Ozinski? - No, Sir.
- 我叫约翰  - 说谎，你喇叭嘴，你是布莉安娜的儿子
- My name's John. - Bullshit, you little prick! You're Briana's kid.
布鲁克林唯一的波多黎各波兰人
The only Puerto Rican Polack in Brooklyn.
哼，我现在跟你们小霸王说，你们对这小子做什麽，我就对你们的妈妈做什麽
Well, I got a deal for you little bully, shit-heels, whatever you do to this guy here, I'm gonna do to your mothers.
知道了吗？同时...拿回去吧
Do you understand? And in the meantime... ride this.
给我滚...小王八....都给我滚，滚回你们的鸟窝
Get outta here, you little... get outta here, get movin' you little shits!
怎样？你还要等书面邀请函吗？
What? Are you waiting for a paper invitation?
- 谁教你打巴掌的？  - 我不知道，先生，本能反应，我想
- Who taught you to slap? - I don't know, Sir, instinct, I guess.
嗯，你最好不要这样
Yeah, well, you need to un-learn that.
- 我有过敏，先生  - 什麽过敏？
- I'm allergic, Sir. - To what?
香淤的烟
Cigarette smoke.
你爸没教过你要保护自己吗？
Your father never taught you to defend yourself?
不，先生，他是和平主义者
No, Sir, he's a pacifist.
嗯，这国家可不是被护树的家伙建立的，我敢确定
Well, this country wasn't founded by tree huggers, that's for sure.
- 你得要保护你自己要不然就会被打倒  - 我很弱小，如果你看的出来的话
- You need to defend yourself or you get mowed down. - I'm small, if you haven't noticed.
- 希特勒也一样  - 这比喻很糟
- Yeah, so was Hitler. - That's a HORRIBLE comparison.
的确是，但我的重点是，小不重要，重点在你的头脑
Indeed! Making a point, though. Small means nothing, it's what's in here.
或是这裡，先生
Or here, Sir.
好吧，伙计，拿篮子
Okay, pal, grab the basket.
这地方很高级
This place is like a mansion.
- 我们上去之后，不淮说话  - 我们要去哪？
- When we get in there, no talkin'. - Where are we going?
你知道，这是你练习不说话的好机会
Ya know, this is a great chance for you to practice no-talkin'.
来吧
C'mon.
- 抱歉我迟到了  - 你来了，医生
- Sorry I'm late. - There you are, Doctor.
- 很高兴见到你，珊蒂，你觉得如何？  - 今天是我生日
- Nice to see you, Sandy, how you feelin'? - Today is my birthday.
喔，生日快乐，你几岁了，17岁吗？
Okay, happy birthday, what are you, seventeen?
喔，你可以把东西放到桌子上吗？
Oh, would you put those things in those drawers?
好吧，珊蒂，我们看看这个听诊器还能不能用
All right, Sandy, let's see how the old ticker's workin'.
你可以跟他们说我不喜欢
Can you tell them I don't like the green beans
切丁的培根放青豆吗？
when they put the bacon bits chopped up in there with them?
太油腻了
It's too greasy for me.
我会说的，珊蒂
Will do, Sandy.
嗯，至少我看的出来，你还是很漂亮
Well, as near as I can tell, you're still beautiful.
也许你需要听我同事的第二意见
Perhaps you require a second opinion from my associate.
很漂亮
Beautiful.
你知道我们有提供洗衣服务，文
You know we can do the laundry here, Vin, we have a service.
- 这让我有事可以做   - 你的小帮手是谁？
- It gives me somethin' to do. - Who's your helper?
- 他价值一小时11元  - 我叫奥利佛
- He's eleven bucks an hour. - It's Oliver, actually.
很高兴认识你，奥利佛，我叫安娜
Nice to meet you, Oliver, I'm Anna.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
- 好吧，谢谢  - 很好
- Okay, thanks. - Okay.
喔，等等，她不喜欢四季豆
Oh, wait, she don't like the string beans.
- 我会记下来，文，她喜欢吃什麽？  - 花椰菜，花椰菜很好
- I'll make a note, Vin, what's she prefer. - Broccoli, broccoli's good.
- 好，太好了  - 路上小心，文
- Okay, great. - Take care, Vin.
时间到
And... time!
- 好吧，刚刚这样只会让你被打得很惨  - 反正我不想打架
- Okay, well, that's just gonna get you beat up pretty bad. - I don't want to fight, anyway.
嗯，没人想要打架，你以为我想要战争吗？
Well, nobody wants to fight, you really think I wanted to go to war?
你以为18岁的大孩子想要坐在稻田中被子弹穿过头吗？
You think and 18 year old kid wants to sit in a rice patty with bullets whizzin' by his head?
- 什麽时候发生的事？  - 越南战争
- When was that? - Vietnam.
- 你当时在场？  - 我想我可以想像
- You were there? - I think I'm imagining' it.
好吧，我要教你一件事，这应该是你
All right, I'm gonna show you one thing, it's probably your
最好方式，如果你做的正确，你就可以打断那个人的鼻子
best shot, if you do it right, ya can break the guy's nose.
- 打断他的鼻子？ - 放轻鬆，你又不会立刻学好
- Break his nose? - Relax, you're not gonna get it right.
好吧，这样
All right, okay.
他比你高大，所以你就压低身子像这样，你蹲下来
He's bigger than you, so you get down below him like this, you squat like this,
这个姿势，然后你用力往上推
this crouch, then you stand up really hard and you push
使尽你全部的力气，一路往上，用你的
all the way through your legs, all the way up, in your
肩膀，你的屁股，全部往上，用力往上推
shoulders, your butt, everything pushes up, and you push all
透过你的手臂往他的鼻子上推
the way through that arm and you go WHACK right in the snoot.
好吧，在我身上试试看，准备？
All right, try it on me. Ya ready?
好吧，但你得做快一点
Okay, but ya gotta do it faster than that, right?
- 玛姬布朗？  - 我有狼牙棒
- Maggie Bronstein? - I have mace!
你的法律文件，金郡家庭法庭，就像大家说的一样「信件已经送达」
I've got papers, Kings County Family Court. As they say, "You've been served."
家庭诉讼案 上诉者大卫布朗
嗯，我得加班，所以我要你帮我
Yeah, I'm gonna work some extra hours, so, I'm gonna cover it.
我不提供打折
I wasn't offerin' a discount.
- 那，你为什麽哭呢？  - 这故事很複杂
- So, whatdya been cryin' about? - It's a long story.
- 重点呢？  - 我前夫想要小孩监护权
- What's the punch line? - My ex wants custody.
那我要工作保险
There goes my job security.
谢谢喔，你这王八蛋
Thanks, you asshole.
不管怎样都会发生
That could've gone either way.
这会有一点凉，知道吗？
It's gonna be cold for a second, okay?
- 快看，这是宝宝的头  - 这头真大
- See there, that's the baby's head. - This is very big head.
- 这是好事吗？  - 这是这个阶段最大的部分
- Maybe good, no? - It's the biggest part at this age.
这是她的小脚
And these are her little legs.
- 她？  - 你不知道吗？
- She? - You didn't know?
- 抱歉，你不想知道吗？  - 不，我很高兴知道
- Sorry, did you not want to know? - No, it's good to know.
- 我无法确认你的保险，麦肯纳先生   - 我们刚结婚
- I couldn't verify with your Insurance, Mr. McKenna. - We are just married.
- 就像这样  - 真的吗？
- That happened. - Really?
嗯，我跟保险公司谈过，你也知道他们动作很慢，我是说官僚还有文书作业
Yeah, I told Insurance, ya know how slow they are? I mean, the bureaucracy, and the paperwork.
我是说，戈北赛跑是什麽
I mean, what is Gobey runnin', anyway?
- 二十元  - 这价格合理吧
- Twenty dollars. - This is good price, no?
对你来说，当然很好
For you, only the best.
- 你值得  - 谢谢你，小甜心
- You're worth it. - Thank you, Sugar Doll.
你拥有我
You owe me lady.
- 给你  - 嗯哼
- Here. - Um-hmm.
- 下次见，小心喔  - 好的，谢谢
- See ya later, take care of yourself.  - Okay, all right.
喔，海，妈
Oh, hi, Mom.
- 你在做什麽？  - 修剪文的草皮
- What are you doing? - Mowing Vin's lawn.
嘿，文
Hey! Vin!
- 我在睡觉，感谢吵醒我  - 为什麽他在修剪你的烂草皮
- I was sleeping, thanks for that. - Why is he mowing your dirt patch?
- 喔，他会付我零用钱  - 我在教他世界的运作方式
- Oh, yeah, he's paying me hourly. - I'm showing him how the world works.
- 你工作，就可以拿到薪水吃喝  - 你在喝酒吗？
- You work, you get paid, you drink. - Are you drinking alcohol?
说真的我不记得了
I honestly don't remember.
好吧，我们回家，我要替你做晚餐，你可以做功课
All right, let's go, I'm gonna make dinner, you can do homework.
- 喔，我已经吃过了  - 你只是在修剪泥土，快走
- Oh, I already ate. - You're mowing dirt, let's go.
他吃饱了，做也我也看过了，我的工作完成了，所以我要休息
He's fed, the homework's checked, I've done my job, I'm takin' a break.
- 明天再付你钱  - 好了，快过来，走了，走了，根本没有草
- Pay day tomorrow. - Okay, come on... let's... leave it, leave it, there's no grass.
再见，文
Bye, Vin.
- 你死了  - 祝你好运
- You're out. - Good luck.
准备接我的红球吧，你这小杂种
Get ready for a red ass, little shit-bag.
祈祷吧，你这娘泡
Say the prayer, you little pussy.
怎麽了，发生什麽事？
What's happened, what happened here?
- 我不知道  - 你不知道
- I do not know. - You don't know!
- 这又不是我的错  - 我看看
- It's not my fault. - Let me see.
你这王八砸碎，狗娘养的
You asshole, dick-bag, son of a whore!
- 你是谁啊？  - 你是谁？
- Who are you? - Who are you?
- 我叫达卡，你是谁？ - 我叫奥利佛
- I am Daka, who are you? - I'm Oliver.
奥利佛，嗯
Oliver... hmm.
- 为什麽你要敲这麽大力？  - 他的听力不好
- Why you bang this door so much? - He's hard of hearing.
- 让他进来  - 不要对我大喊
Let him in! Don't yell at me.
你打断他的鼻子？
You broke his nose?
没错，先生，我想没错，他的鼻血流的到处都是，你应该看看
Yes, Sir, I think so, there was blood everywhere, you should've seen it.
我希望可以看看，你一定是做得很好，让我看看
I wish I had... You must've got him just right.. show me.
- 你教他怎麽打架？  - 他是小矮子
- You teach him fighting? - He's a little runt.
你知道，他需要学习怎麽保护自己
Ya know, he gotta learn how to defend himself.
王八蛋才打架
Fighting is for assholes.
- 我的钱呢？  - 在梳妆台上
- Where's my money? - It's on the dresser.
- 已经扣掉花费了   - 你根本不会教小孩
- Minus the co-pay. - You don't teach children.
看看你
Look at you.
打断他的鼻子
Break his nose.
她是谁啊？
Who is she?
- 「夜晚的淑女」 - 那是什麽？
- A "lady of the night". - What's that?
一种最诚实的工作方式
It's one of the more honest ways to make a living.
看板上会写今天的活动，比赛号码，谁在跑，谁在骑，等等
The board tells us the action for the day, race number, who's running, who's riding, and so forth.
- 20/1是什麽？  - 那是赔率
- What's twenty slash one? - That's odds.
拉斯维加斯的赌徒认为这匹马有1/20的机会赢
Some bookie out of Vegas thinks that horse has a 1 in 20 chance of winning.
- 如果他赢了会怎样？  - 你就可以拿到20倍的钱
- What do you get if he does? - Twenty times your money.
- 那还真不错  - 如果赢的话，当然
- That's a good deal. - If you win, sure.
- 脚上绑起来的马跟狗一样  - 听起来不像称讚
- That one with the wraps is a dog. - Doesn't sound like a compliment.
对马来说不好，牠的赔率跟天文数字一样
Not for a horse,  the odds of him winning are astronomical.
赔率越大，金额越大，我们应该全部压在牠身上
Long odds, bigger pay-off, we should take him across the board.
想太多了，孩子
Don't get ahead of yourself, kid.
- 你在祈祷吗？  - 祈祷？
- Are you praying? - Praying?
- 看起来很像  - 我以为我们说过你不淮说话
- That's what it looks like. - I thought we talked about you not talking.
什麽叫三连胜？
What's a trifecta?
你选三头马，按照一、二、三顺序完成比赛
You pick three horses, 1, 2, 3 in the order they finish.
- 高风险但是高报酬  - 听起来不可能
- High risk and reward. - Sounds improbable.
嗯，如果你要赌博，你就得赢大一点
Well, if you're gonna gamble, you might as well have a chance to win big.
哈维最棒、甜心女士、香槟笛子...一、二、三
Harvey Knows Best, Sweeter Lady, Champagne Flute... 1,2,3.
八百分之一
Eight hundred to one.
- 你有钱吗？  - 有啊
- You got any money? - Sure.
七块钱
Seven dollars.
- 这是什麽？午餐钱？  - 没错
- What is that, lunch money? - Yes, Sir.
那你可能会学得很痛苦
Well, you might as well learn the hard way.
我也下点钱，减轻你的痛苦
I'll throw in some too, that's called mitigation.
- 什麽减轻？  - 你下七块钱，我下三块
- What's "mitigation"? - That's where you throw in 7, and I throw in 3.
加油，加油
Come on, come on.
这真酷
This is really cool.
不要停！不要停！不要停！不要停！
Do not stop! Don't stop! Don't stop! Don't stop!
这真不公平，不公平
It isn't fair! It's not fair!
我们赢了，是吗？
We won... didn't we?
不要说出来，不要说出来，假装你没赢
Just roll with it, just roll with it, man, just roll with it, like you didn't win it.
- 该死  - 不，不会吧，又没赢
- Shot! - No! No! It didn't work for me.
你知道吗？我们没赢，我们一毛钱都没有
Do you understand me? We... we didn't win at all, we didn't win anything, okay?
午安，麦肯纳先生
Good afternoon. Mr. McKenna.
我要替我孙子开一个帐户
I need to open up a savings account for grandson.
这是让我的帐户归零的钱，顺便替我关闭我的帐户
And this'll get my account up to zero. Close me out while you're tapping away over there.
以后不要当会计师，他们没有骨气
Don't ever become a pencil-pusher, kid, they're spineless.
你好，布朗女士，我是丹欧布莱恩，圣派翠克小学的校长
Hello, Mrs. Bronstein, this is Dan O'Brien, Principal here at St. Patrick.
几天前，你的儿子奥利佛在学校打架
A few days ago, your son Oliver was involved in a fight at school.
- 我们一直想连络你  - 什麽？
- We tried to reach you... - What?
如果你是推销员，请留言，这样我就不需要打给你
If you're a telemarketer, please leave a message so I can NOT return your call.
文？文？奥利佛？奥利佛？我是妈，快接电话
Vin? Vin? Oliver? Oliver, it's Mom, pick up. Hello?
- 你还想喝吗？  - 嗯，麻烦了
- You want another? - Yes, please.
你自己叫吧，我们今天要开心一点
Go for it, we're livin' today.
- 不好意思，先生  - 你蠢孩子
- Excuse me, Sir. - You kids, pimp small-talkers.
你要是不大叫，没人听的到
There's no point in yappin', 'cause no one's listenin'
- 再来一次  - 不好意思，先生
- Let's hear it. - Excuse me, Sir!!
要是没听到就什麽都没有
Ya can't get nothin' in this world without bein' heard.
- 再来一杯可乐，谢谢  - 也再给我来一杯，罗杰
- Another coke, please. - You can hit me, too, Rog.
你的波本酒卖光了，你把我喝光了
We're out of your bourbon, ya cleaned me out.
- 不要骗我，像个男人  - 文，他根本不能进来酒吧
- Don't lie to me, be a man. - Vin! And he's not supposed to be sittin' at the bar.
你说的对，我们得找其他地方花光钱
You're right, we're gonna go somewhere else to spend our money.
嘿，他只是在做他的工作，好心一点
Hey, he's only doin' his job, Dead Man, be nice.
该死
Damn.
- 安珀，拿急救箱  - 只是割到手，我常这样
- Amber, get the first aid kit. - It's just a cut, I got lots of 'em.
来，给你
Yeah, here.
- 你的血沾到吧檯了  - 没关系，小孩子得做作业了
- You're bleedin' all over the bar. - That's fine, kid's gotta do homework.
来吧，我们走了
Come on, let's go.
海，妈
Hi, Mom.
- 你去哪裡了，你的车呢？文  - 坏掉了
- Where were you, where the hell's your car, Vin? - It broke down.
- 坏掉了  - 喔，坏掉了，真的吗？
- It broke down. - Oh, it broke down, really!
我不喜欢你没问过我就带他乱走
I don't appreciate you taking him anywhere without asking me.
- 哇，真有趣  - 你可不可以放聪明一点，好吗
- Whoa, this is gonna be fun. - Can you not be a smart-ass, just for once, okay?
我要知道我儿子的行踪，好吗？
I want to know where my son is at all times, okay?
- 我们去吃东西  - 要让他挨饿吗？
- We just went to eat. - He should starve?
进去，奥利佛
Go in the house, Oliver.
- 妈  - 进去，奥利佛
- Mom. - Go in the house, Oliver
- 晚安，文  - 嗯，我们明天见
- Good night, Vin. - Yeah, we'll see about that.
你知道他在学校打架吗？
You know he's getting into fights at school, did you know that?
嗯，他有提过
Yeah, he mentioned something like that.
是吗，他并没有跟我说过这件事
Yeah, well, he didn't mention anything to me about it.
喔，也许你不知道，但因为你不常在家
Oh, well, maybe you haven't noticed, but you haven't been home much.
跟一个不常在家的人有点难沟通
It's kinda difficult to have a conversation with someone that's not here.
喔，我们要这样吗？
Oh, we're going to do that?
天啊，我最喜欢像你这种人给我建议，特别是为人父母
God, I love when somebody like you tells somebody like me advice, especially on parenting.
我的服务不包含被你骂，所以我要加到一小时十五块
I didn't sign on for the hormones, deary, so that's gonna cost you 15 bucks an hour.
你知道你为什麽没小孩吗？
You know why you never had kids?
因为你从不为别人著想只想到你自己
Because you don't want to think about anybody other than yourself.
你又知道我什麽？说真的，跟我说啊
What do you know about me? Really? Tell me, I'd love it.
没有，我一点都不知道你，就像你想的那样
Nothing, I don't know a thing about you, just the way you want it,
你可以继续像个浑蛋让大家都远离你
and then you can act like a prick and it keeps everybody away.
- 「如果没有打断...」 - 已经打断了，文，你自己看看
- "If it ain't broken..." - It is broken, Vin, take a look at it.
喔，好吧，那我这星期工作40小时，或是41小时，超过半小时算一小时
Oh, all right, I'm at forty hours for this week, at forty-one I go to time and a half.
不好意思，有人能付我钱吗？
Excuse me, someone gonna pay me?
开什麽玩笑啊
You gotta be kidding me.
- 我根本说不出这些词  - 其实很有创意
- I can't even say these words. - They're creative.
他一口气说的
That's one way to put it.
在他这个年纪换到新学校都很难熬，或是任何年纪
Adjusting to a new school is tough on children at this age, at any age, really, and I don't
我不想特别指什麽，但有没有任何我们需要注意的事？
want to minimize that...but is there anything else going on that we should be aware of?
- 喔，我根本不晓得从哪裡开始讲  - 他的父亲呢？
- Oh, I wouldn't even know where to start. - How about his father?
- 嗯，我不想浪费你们的时间  - 我们有很多时间
- Well, I don't want to take up all your time. - We have all the time.
我们正在办离婚
We're in the middle of a divorce.
奥利佛的父亲跟他的助理有外遇，还有会计
Oliver's father was having an affair with his assistant, and their accountant,
还有我的髮型设计师，她还是替我弄头髮，很有趣
And my hairdresser, while she was still doing my hair, so that was fun.
现在他想要奥利佛的监护权，全部的监护权
And now he's filed for custody for Oliver... full custody
他在得到想要的东西之前不会给任何援助
and he won't pay any support until he gets what he wants.
- 还有，他是律师  - 该死
- Plus, he's a lawyer. - Shit.
所以我只能儘可能带著奥利佛离开的越快越好
So, I just had to get out of there as fast as I could and I took Oliver with me.
我在密西丘找到工作，我是断层扫描工程师，所以我每天工作都很忙
And I got a job at Mission Hills, I'm a C.A.T. scan tech, so I just see really rough stuff all day.
你知道，我每天都在看癌症、肿瘤、囊肿和血块，但我不能说
You know, cancer and tumors and cysts and clots and I see what I'm looking at but I can't tell
其他人都依靠我，所以我每天都很悲惨
you know, the people that are laying there, so, that's miserable all day,
我每天都工作到很晚，因为我想公私分明
and I work really late, because I'm trying to get our act together.
这就是他在这裡的原因，因为他可以受到良好教育
That's why he's here, so he can have a good education.
我想要让奥利佛过的正常一点，但我却要处理大卫的事，还有...
And I'm trying to give him a semi-normal life, and I'm dealing with this shit from David, and...
我真的很抱歉他说葬话
I'm really am sorry about swearing.
我知道他不想要生小孩，他根本不想要奥利佛
I know he didn't even want kids... he didn't want him.
他只是想这麽做让我不开心，你知道奥利佛是被领养的吗？你们知道吗？
He's just doing this so I'm not happy. You know Oliver's adopted? Did you know that?
我不知道你们会怎麽做....但他...
I don't know how you would be... he is, and...
我生不出小孩
I cannot have kids.
你知道，我的输卵管打结...我想...
You know, something about my fallopian tubes being twisted... I think...
我认为我的身体在反抗大卫的精虫
what I REALLY think is that they were just recoiling from David's sperm.
我....可以...给我一张...谢谢
I... can... just have one... thank you.
所以，嗯，我经历了这麽多事
So, uh... to think that all of this has permeated,
你知道，奥利佛的小事，我是说...
you know, Oliver's whole, little being, right? I mean...
一定得，他就像是小...小海绵一样
it'd have to, he's like a little... like a little sponge.
我的真名叫罗伯特，奥兹是我的姓
My real name's Robert, Ozinski's my last name.
从去年盖瑞叫我之后大家都开始这样叫
People called me that ever since Gary called me that last year, now everyone calls me that.
我根本没办法说
We can't go around 'em:
「嘿，蠢蛋们，不要叫我奥兹，我叫罗伯特」
"Hey, Dubois, don't call me Ozinski, my name's Robert."
现在我却要花上整天做这些事
Now I spend my whole life doin' that.
- 你在尿尿？  - 抱歉，我忍不住
- You takin' a whiz? - Sorry, can't hold it.
罗伯特是我霸的名字，我是二世
Robert was my dad's name, I'm a Junior.
他不在我身边，我其实也不认识他，他在我还是婴儿的时候就离开了
He's not around, though, I don't really know him 'cause he left when I was a baby.
嗯，我爸也不在我身边，他对我妈做了些坏事
Yeah, my dad's not around either, he did some bad things
所以我们离开他，我已经有段时间没看到他了
to my mom and so we left and I haven't seen him in a while.
我有点想他，我妈有点坏
I kinda miss him, though, my Mom's being a jerk.
他们都是这样，老兄
They do that, man.
- 你爸教你怎麽打架的吗？  - 不，是我的保母
- Your dad the one that taught ya how ta fight? - No, my babysitter.
一天会涨潮两次，医生
The tide comes in twice a day, Doctor.
嗯，潮汐就是这样，涨潮退潮
Yeah, that's a tide, comes and goes.
我等不及秋天到来，水边种满了最漂亮的菊花
I can't wait for Autumn, they plant the most beautiful mums all around the water.
变成所有你想像的到的颜色，我不知道怎麽会这样
Every color you can imagine. I don't know where they get them all.
去植物园买的吧
At the garden store.
你总是很幽默，文
You've always been so funny, Vin.
文
Vin.
文，就是文，珊蒂
Vin, it's Vin, Sandy.
鸭子会吃掉植物
The ducks eat them, though.
我们得赶走鸭子，很可惜
We have to shoo them away, it such a shame.
很可惜
It's a shame.
我们有很多种你可负担的照顾选择，文
There's plenty of affordable health care options, Vin.
我想你也知道，阳光居的价格不是人人都负担的起
I'm sure you know that, Sunnyside is pricey, not for everyone.
珊蒂得受到最好的照顾，我只是，我还在想办法
My Sandy gets the best, I just... I'll just have to figure it out.
我了解，但你已经拖延几个月了，我们不是做慈善事业，你也知道
I understand that, but you're months behind and we are not in the credit business, as you know.
什麽意思？
What's that mean?
我们需要预先付三个月的全额
We need payment in full and three months in advance.
- 了解  - 下星期前
- Got it. - By next week.
- 下星期？ - 嗯，下星期
- Next week? - Yeah, next week.
嗯，我可以先付20%，够诚恳了吧
Well, I can give you 20 percent. In good faith?
文，好意心领了，抱歉
Vin, we're passed good faith, I'm sorry.
我们会将珊蒂转院到其他你需要的地方
We will transfer Sandy wherever you want to put her.
转院？
Put her?
就这样？
That's it? Or we get the boot?
我想这不算是最好的说法
I don't think that's the best way to phrase what's happening.
好吧，那更好的说法是什麽？
Okay, what's the best way to phrase it?
就是这样
It is what it is.
- 可以在她的房间摆些新植物吗？  - 我可以加订一些
- Let's get some new plants for the room, okay? - I can have the desk order somethin'.
- 嗯，我想要放菊花  - 没问题
- Well, I was hopin' maybe for mums. - Sure.
还有，这是给你添麻烦的小费
And ah... here's a little somethin' for your trouble.
不行，文，这本来就是我的工作，我照顾每个人，不要这样
No! Vin! This is my job, I take care of people, please.
你做超过你的工作了，安娜，你就像珊蒂的天使
You go WAY beyond your job, Anna, you've been an angel to my Sandy.
- 好吧，文，但以后不要这样，好吗？  - 也不会，我破产了
- Okay, Vin, we don't make it habit now, okay? - It can't happen, I'm shit broke.
你的微笑很美，你应该多笑意点，我去拿衣服
Ya got a nice smile, ya should do it more often. I'll get the laundry.
给你
There ya go.
- 少了很多  - 她这星期不太换衣服
- It's a lot lighter. - She didn't change much this week.
嗯，我的车会轻一点
Well... easy on my back.
- 谢谢  - 你自己小心，文
- Thanks. - Behave yourself, Vin.
他愿意付一百元
He'll pay hundred dollars.
一百元，我拿处方籤花的还更多
A hundred dollars, I pay more than that for one prescription.
他说，这是治疗癫痫，前列腺烧灼还有软便
He said, this is for epilepsy, for prostate flaring and to soften the shitting.
- 这还是有点价值啊 - 给谁用啊？你吗？
- That should add some value. - For who? You?
我们需要，我需要...五百元
We need the... I need the dough. I... 500 bucks!
- 这都是高价值的垃圾  - 他说一百元，文
- This is all high-dollar shit. - He said one hundred, Vin.
接受或是离开，你也不能当毒品卖
You take it or leave it, you can't sell this to get high.
我愿意拿一百块
I'll take the hundred.
喔，你愿意拿一百块，蠢蛋
Oh, you take the hundred. Stupid.
- 你的帐户已经关闭了，麦肯纳先生  - 是，我知道
- Your account's closed, Mr. McKenna. - Yeah, I know that.
这次我要结清我孙子的帐户，我想我有资格
This withdraw is on my grandson's account, I think I'm on it.
- 你要多少？先生  - 总共多少？
- How much, Sir? - What's the balance?
2700元
Twenty-seven hundred.
- 我全部都要  - 你要拿大钞还是小钞
- I'll take all of it. - How'd you like that?
一百元钞票，谢谢
Hundreds, please.
这是2700元，赖瑞
It's twenty-seven hundred, Larry,
我要买450元的第三场的三连胜
I want a four hundred and fifty dollar trifecta box in the third, okay.
一、二、三，幸运林肯，新黛咪，山米的储蓄
One, two, three. Lucky Lincoln, New Dime, Sammy's Saving.
谢谢你
Thank you, Sir.
- 这次会让一切翻转  - 好的
- This is gonna make it all better. - Okay.
你还好吗？
You all right, hon?
不，我不好
No, I'm not.
你一定认为我不是认真的人，文尼
You must think I'm not a very serious person, Vinny.
- 你没资格来这裡  - 你找到什麽值钱的东西吗？
- You have no right to be here! - You find anything good?
不，只有些旧珠宝，不值多少钱
Naw, some old jewelry, not worth much.
- 那是我妻子的东西，你这浑蛋  - 你欠我钱
- That's my wife's, you son of a bitch. - You owe me money.
拜託，文尼，为什麽你一定要让事情这麽难做
Come on, Vinny! Why do you always have to do things the hard way?
- 这样比较有趣  - 你会很痛苦
- It's more interesting. - And a lot more painful.
好吧，来吧
All right, let's do.
- 这家伙疯了  - 别杀了他，但让他生不如死
- This son of a bitch is crazy. - Don't kill him, but bring him close to it.
怎麽...？
What the...?
- 你在干嘛？老头  - 他要死了，老兄
- What are you doing, old man? - He's dyin', boo.
不，他不会，他...
No he's not, he's...
不要碰任何东西，我们走吧
Don't touch nothin', let's just go.
文，我是麦姬，我们要把你放进仪器哩，我们要做些测试
Vin, it's Maggie, we're gonna put you in this machine, and we're gonna take some tests
- 这不会痛   - 他根本听不到，玛姬
- and it's not gonna hurt a bit. - He can't understand you, Maggie.
好吧，就这样，就这样，这要花上几分钟
Okay, there he is, there he is, okay, it's just gonna be a couple of minutes.
- 我勇敢的小家伙  - 他还好吗？
- There's my brave, little man. - Is he okay?
我以为他死了
I thought he was dead.
- 他飞上天堂了  - 嗯，看起来很像
- He's flyin', then. - Yeah, that's what it looks like.
- 他看起来也很像喝醉了   - 我不想知道你们在做什麽
- He looks like that when he's drunk, too, so... - I don't even know what you're doin' anymore.
我只知道我在做什麽，你爸明天会在法院上大做文章
I know what I'm doin', your father's gonna have a field day with this.
我...我要不是因为你也不会这样槓上他，我要...
I wouldn't... I wouldn't be here instead of with you if it wasn't for him, ya know, I'm gonna get...
妈，我们没事的，你每天都认真工作，我们需要这笔钱
Mom, we're doin' good, you're working hard every day, and we need the money.
一切都没事的
It's all right.
他到底怎麽了？
What's wrong with him, anyway?
文尼中风了
Vinny's had a stroke.
慢一点，往下，往下，往下，很好
Slowly! Down, down, down, down, down, good.
膝盖弯曲，腰挺直，很好
Bend the knees, flat back, good, good.
膝盖弯曲，再下来一点，再下来一点，好，好
Bend the knees, a little bit, a little bit. All right, all right, good.
我选择圣威廉罗切斯特，收养小孩的圣人
I chose St. William of Rochester, the patron saint of adopted children.
其实这故事很有趣，我看过其它的圣人，都很，神圣
It's a pretty interesting story, all the other saint I looked at were all so... saintly, I guess.
「神圣」的意思是什麽？
What does "saintly" mean to you?
我不知道，我其实不相信圣人
I don't know, I don't really believe in saints and all that.
我觉得圣威廉成为圣人只是因为他收养小男孩后被杀
I feel like St. William just got to be a saint because he's killed by the boy he adopted.
现在，人们常常被杀，但并没有因此变成圣人
These days, people get killed all the time, and they don't get to be a saint for it.
好吧，谢谢你，奥利佛
All right, well, thanks, Oliver.
虽然小奥利佛不愿回应，但我正好相信现在还是充满圣人
Despite young Oliver's reticence, I DO happen to believe there are saints all around us today.
也许他们并不是受到信仰成为圣人，但他们跟课本上的人一样重要
They may never be considered as such by a religion, but they are just as important as the ones in your textbooks.
因此，你们要回去找你们认识，或知道
Thus, you are going to research someone you know, or know of,
并判断他们是否有资格成为圣人
and determine if they have the qualities fit for sainthood.
- 他在哪？他的车在这  - 他在医院
- Where is he? His car is here. - He's in the hospital.
怎麽了？
For what?
- 你怎麽跟文森特认识的？  - 我替他工作
- So, how did you and Vincent know each other? - I'm working for this man.
喔，做什麽？
Oh! Doing what?
工作，我是舞者
Working. I work for dancer.
听起来真刺激
Sounds exciting.
试著说说看
Try to sound it out.
不对
Not quite.
你看起来并没有失去幽默感
You didn't lose your sense of humor.
- 嘿，文森特，你有访客了  - 我只会待五分钟
- Hey! Vincent! You got some visitors. - I stay five minutes only.
医院是个烂地方
Hospital is shit place.
你看起来好多了，文
You look a lot better, Vin.
你说什麽？
What'd ya say?
文森
Vince.
我们给文多一点时间复健吧
How about we just give Vin some time to do his therapy.
谢谢你，可能需要一个小时
Thank you. It'll be about an hour.
- 下地狱吧，一个小时  - 也许不用一个小时
- Go to hell. An hour. - Maybe less.
为什麽你这麽坏，你可以去死啦，浑蛋
Why are you so mean, you could stop breathing. Asshole.
- 好吧，我们，嘿，我们买些零食吃吧  - 谢谢，我饿死了
- Okay, how 'bout we... hey, we get him a snack, want a snack? - Thanks, I'm starving.
你知道，他们做的事是让测试他的肌肉跟舌头的反应
Ya know, they does things that his muscles and his mouth'll respond to therapy.
所以，这是好事
So, that's good.
- 他看起来...  - 就跟智障一样
- He sounds... - Like the retard.
嗯，他还是好人，所以讲他智障差不多
Well, he's still good man anyway, so the retard is not that far.
你有一块钱吗？我很饿，我整天都没吃东西
Do you have dollar, I'm starving, I eat nothing today?
- 嗯，我可能有  - 嗯
- Here, I probably have something. - Yeah.
一块半更好
Maybe dollar half is better.
- 好吧  - 谢谢
- All right. - Spasiba.
她怀的是文森的...
Is that Vince's...?
- 婴儿吗？ - 嗯
- baby? - Yeah.
我不太介入他的私事
I'd like to stay away from the whole situation.
- 而且问一个女人是否怀孕很不礼貌  - 嗯，我想她很明显是怀孕了
- It's not polite to ask a woman if she's pregnant. - Well, I think it's pretty obvious that she' pregnant.
文看起来90岁了，妈...
Vin's like 90 something, Mom...
嘿，如果你踢贩卖机，就会多掉一个，这样你就有两个了，不错吧
If you kick this machine, its first candy drops, you can get two to come down, it's good, no?
谢谢你
Thank you.
嗯，真该死
Well, cocksucker.
不要吃这麽快，你这蠢猫
Don't eat fast, stupid cat.
我...
I...
我想要新鲜的粪
I will want fresh crap.
「螃蟹」不是粪
"Crab", not "crap".
螃蟹
Crab.
不是「粪」
Not "crap".
好吧
Okay.
钱
Money.
不，这是...这是「树」
No, it's a... it's a "t"... tree.
你欠我钱，你破坏我的树
You owe me money. No, you broke my tree.
- 好，我知道...  - 嗯，你破坏了我的篱笆
- Yeah, I know... - Yeah, you broke my fence, too.
你是故意放进去的吗？
Are you planting these?
- 来，这你应该知道  - 仙人掌
- Here, this should be familiar. - Cactus.
不，「刺」
No, "prick".
刺伤人的刺
Big prick.
很好，很好
Wonderful, wonderful.
达卡很漂亮
Daka is beautiful.
我知道你想要按摩或是...跳舞，不要想奉承我，没用的
I know you just want special massage or something... dance later, don't try charm me, it doesn't work.
别担心，你会好起来的
Don't worry, okay, it's going to get better.
现在，我要加速了
Now, I've got to stay calm.
抱歉赢过你了
I'm sorry.
怎麽变乾淨了？
Where's all my dirt?
保持整齐
Keep clean this house.
- 这是什麽？  - 蔬菜
- What's all that? - Vegetables.
不要吃，你不知道蔬菜吗？
Get out of that! You don't know this vegetables?
我知道，但我不吃...我不吃
I do, but... I don't eat... I don't eat 'em.
你现在开始吃，而且你要按时付费，好吗
You do now, and you pay me for the hours now, papa, okay?
- 什麽？  - 我照顾你
- What... for? - I take care of you.
我们不再干肮葬是了好吗，所以不要问，你太老了，而且我太胖了
And we don't bump the ugly parts no more, okay, so don't ask, you're too old for this and I'm too fat.
一个小时十五块，加上住宿和食物
Fifteen dollars for the hours plus room and food.
- 我的秘密醃黄瓜呢？   - 好吧
- I get my secret pickles? - Okay.
-谁是文森特麦肯那？ - 你认识他吗？
- Who is Vincent McKenna? - Do you know him?
他..他是邻居，他有时候会照顾奥利佛
Just... he's... he's a neighbor, and he sometimes watches Oliver.
法官大人，他是我当事人的邻居，他偶尔会照顾奥利佛
Your Honor, he is my client's neighbor, he occasionally watches Oliver sometimes.
他是你的保母？
He's your babysitter?
他算吧，我有付钱，奥利佛放学后会去他家，因为我还在工作
He's worth it, I pay him, Oliver, ya know, goes over there for a few hours after school... I'm still at work.
他是保母，法官大人，有付费关系
He's a babysitter, Your Honor, of sorts, a paid position.
- 我可以请教为什麽问吗？  - 你的当事人知道
- May I ask why this is relevant? - Is your client aware
麦肯纳先生带她儿子去赛马场赌博吗？
that Mr. McKenna takes her son to the racetrack and they gamble?
他也带奥利佛去酒吧
He also take him to a local bar.
- 我们去看马，几次  - 几次？很有趣吗？
- We went to the horses... a few times. - A few times? Is that fun?
- 有一点  - 是吗？好吧
- A little. - Yeah? Good.
我....我完全没听过，我以前都不知道
I... this is... completely news to me... I never heard this before.
我的当事人并不知情，我也是，所以很惊讶，到目前为止
My client is unaware of these events... as am I, which is a big surprise, right now.
我想你们看到这些资料也会很惊讶
I'll bet there are quite a few surprises in this folder then.
喔，天啊
Oh, God.
达卡帕拿，你知道她的职业吗？
Daka Paramova. Are you aware of her occupation?
她替文森工作？她替文森工作对吧？
She works for Vince? She works for Vince, right?
- 她是夜晚的淑女  - 什麽？
- She's The Lady of the Night. - What?
- 你知道这什麽意思吗？  - 她在晚上工作？
- Do you know what that means? - She works at night?
她害我们陷入这个情况
She'd pay me a part of it.
法官大人，我需要跟我的当事人讨论一下
Your Honor, I need a few minutes to confer with my client.
我想你们需要
I imagine you do.
我猜在赛马场赌博就是数学课，是吗，你们学怎麽赌博
I guess gambling in a racetrack is like math class, huh, you gonna learn how to bet.
是赔率
The odds.
- 还有酒吧，我想这叫做「时事」？ - 比较像是「社会研究」
- The bar, guess that could fall under "current events", right? - More like "social studies".
那个脱衣舞嚷，我想不到什麽藉口
It's the strip club hooker I can't seem to get my head around.
「经济学」？「生物学」？
"Commerce"? "Biology"?
不要说了，别说话
Just stop talking... don't talk.
为什麽你会以为我听不到？
Why do you people think my people can't hear?
什麽样的人会把小孩带去赛马跟酒吧
What kind of a man takes a child to the bar and to the racetrack?
还让他跟妓女一起混
And has him hangin' out with a prostitute?
什麽样的母亲会让他的儿子跟这种人在一起？
What kind of mother lets her son hang out with a man like that?
你是大浑球，文
You're an asshole, Vin.
我得跟他父亲共同监护权，都要感谢你
Fifty-fifty custody with his asshole dad and I have you to thank for that.
你除了你自己不能责怪任何人
You have no one but yourself to blame for that.
他需要比赖帐的母亲更好的人
He needs more than a deadbeat mother.
说的好
Good one.
也许我的确活该，我不知道我在想什麽让他跟你在一起
Maybe I deserve that, I don't know what the hell I was thinkin' lettin' him hang out with you.
我也这麽认为
My sentiments exactly.
算了，他不会在过去你家了，就这样，我去拿钱赔你的蠢树
Well, he's not comin' over there anymore, that's a given, and I'll get your money for your stupid tree.
- 还有利息  - 是喔，算你赚到
- There'll be some interest. - Yeah, good luck with that.
喔，我很抱歉...抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry... sorry.
- 我的反应有时候会比较慢  - 你永远也快不起来，只是蠢而已
- My reaction time's much slower these days - Yeah, you were never fast... just stupid.
你有七通新留言
You have seven new messages.
你好，文，我是阳光居的安娜
Hello, Vin, this is Anna here... from Sunnyside.
我很遗憾有些关于你妻子，珊蒂的坏消息
I'm afraid we have some bad news regarding your wife, Sandy, Sir..
请儘速回电
Please call us as soon as you get this.
文，你好，我是阳光居的安娜
Vin? Hello, it's Anna again, at Sunnyside.
我们尚未接到你的回电
We haven't heard back from you regarding Sandy.
请儘速回电
Please call us right away.
文森特，我们留了许多通知，尚未接到你的回电
Vincent, we've left a few messages for you... haven't heard back.
我们很需要你的消息
We really need to hear from you about Sandy.
请儘速回电
Please call or come by as soon as possible.
好吧，文，这些是珊蒂的遗物
Here we go, Vin. All of Sandy's personal items are in there.
- 我老婆在哪裡  - 她死了，文
- My wife, where is she? - She died, Vin.
- 我知道，她的尸体在哪？  - 在裡面
- I know that, where is she? - She's in there.
- 哪裡？  - 箱子裡
- Where? - In the box.
她的骨灰，文
Her remains, Vin.
她几个星期前过世，我们联络过你好几次
She died a few weeks ago. We tried contacting you several times.
因为我们一直没接到你的消息，所以我们决定
And when we didn't hear back from you, we decided to go ahead
按照你之前的决定，你要火化她
with your death directives, you wanted her cremated.
- 她就在箱子裡？ - 骨灰，没错
- She's in that box? - Her remains are, Vin.
就在箱子裡，在箱子裡面
Yes, in a box... inside that box.
我很遗憾，文
I am sorry for your loss, Vin.
这地方很平静
This place is peace.
以前是
It was.
- 不，我有唸书  - 我从来没念书
- Naw, I study. - I never study.
- 好吧，再见  - 嗯，再见
- Okay, I'll see ya later. - Yeah, see ya later, man.
- 好哇  - 再见，奥利佛
- All right. - Later, Oliver.
- 嘿，作业很多吗？  - 不，只有美术跟数学
- Hey, ya got a lot of homework? - No, arts and math.
- 她要跟在我们身边？  - 嗯，是你爸找的秘密保母
- Is she with us? - Yeah, she's your father's idea of secret child care.
- 她叫什麽名字？ - 你有嘴巴，自己问
- What's her name? - You have a voice, you ask her.
- 不好意思，你叫甚麽名字？ - 爱梅达
- Excuse me, what your name? - Emelda.
- 你好，爱梅达  - 你好，奥利佛先生
- Hi, Emelda. - Hola, Mr. Oliver.
她每天都会在吗？
Is she every day?
周末还会跟你到你爸那边
And every other weekend when you're gonna go to your Dad's.
情况就是这样，小家伙，你要在我跟你爸之间来来回回
It's what it's gonna be now, bub, you're gonna get shuffled back and forth between me and him.
嗯，他是我爸嘛
Well, he is my dad.
我知道他出轨很多次，所以我们离开他
I know he cheated on you a of bunch of times and that's why we left him.
你还要听吗？
Really?
你怎麽知道？
How do you know that?
你跟很多人说过，奶奶，茱蒂阿姨，其他的表哥表姊
You'll tell anybody who'll listen... Grandma, Aunt Judy, all the cousins.
你的脸书状态没有改吗？
How's your Facebook status?
你知道，我一直很想改，但...
Ya know, I've been meaning to change that, I...
- 我改成单身吧  - 嗯，这样比较好
- should just say I'm single. - Yeah, that's better.
- 替代我的人？  - 嗯，我想是
- My replacement? - Yeah, I guess so.
我很不想举报你妈请非法移民...
I'd hate to have to report your mother to immigration and natur...
我是美国人
I am a citizen.
奥利佛先生，只有一分钟
Mr. Oliver, one minute.
- 盒子裡是什麽？  - 我老婆
- What's in the box? - My wife.
- 她死了？ - 没有
- She died? - No.
她缩小了，她现在住在裡面
She shrunk herself, she's livin' in there now.
不用租金
Rent free.
我很遗憾，文...你的损失
Sorry, Vin... for your loss.
我从来搞不懂为什麽要说这句话
Never understood why people say that.
我们不知道要说什麽
They don't know what else to say.
怎不说「她以前长怎样？」「你想念她吗？」或是「你现在要做什麽？」
How about: "What was she like?", "Do you miss her?"or "What are you gonna do now?"
帮你自己一个忙，好好过生活
Do yourself a favor, get a life.
不要像我一样
Stop livin' mine.
好好记住，不要浪费在我这种废人身上
Take my word, it's not workin' for shit for me.
- 这不是事实  - 你以为我是什麽样的人？
- That's not true. - What the hell do you know about me?
你根本不认识我，你只是蠢蛋
You don't know me, you're just stupid.
我当然很蠢
Of course I'm stupid.
大部分人只认为你是喝醉的坏老头
Mostly for thinking you're more that just a drunk, mean, old man.
我想可以说再见了
Guess that's goodbye.
你很悲伤，悲伤的人
You're sad.
我喜欢你到了月亮，珊蒂
I loved you to the moon there, Sandy.
满月
A June moon.
好吧，两个星期，两星期后要报告你们的圣人
All right, 2 weeks, 2 weeks to Are Saints Among Us assembly.
到时候你的努力要在舞台上展现
The grand culmination of your sizable efforts on one great stage.
不要忘记邀请你的父母，重要的人，老婆，女朋友
Don't forget to invite your parents, significant others, et cetera, wives, girlfriends,
还有好好享受，还有发表时禁止骂葬话，奥兹
and enjoy yourselves, and no expletives in your presentation please Ozinski.
他不喜欢被叫奥斯，杰拉蒂老师，他不喜欢
He doesn't like Ozinski, Brother Geraghty, never has.
我叫罗伯特，老师
My names Robert, Sir.
- 他没跟你讲过他以前是军人？  - 没有，先生
- He didn't tell you he was a soldier? - No, Sir.
他以前是士官长，很有名
A sergeant major of all things, he's famous.
但这太贵了
But it's too expensive,
我不知道怎麽...这很便宜欸
I don't know how to... ... it's cheap enough.
- 喔，这一个，很棒欸  - 女士，不好意思，这价格标错了
- Oh! This one, this is good. - Ma'am, I'm sorry, this is the wrong price.
不，不，不，我喜欢
No, no, no, I like this.
我喜欢这个
I love this.
我们可以买这个吗？我们付得起
Can we get this? We can afford this.
- 女士  - 我喜欢，我想要
- Ma'am... - I like this! I want this!
我们可以带走吗，好，带走吧
Can we take? Okay, I'll take it.
- 就是那个老人？  - 嗯，他以前在越南
- That's the old guy? - Yeah, he was in Vietnam.
- 那是哪一个州？  - 那是国家
- Did I study the States? - It's a country.
州是在国家之内
States are inside countries.
请不要将东西放置在婴儿的脖子周围
"Do not place items with string around child's neck,"
「例如头套，细绳，奶嘴绳」
"such as hoods, strings, or pacifier cords.".
细绳可能造成窒息
"Strings can cause strangulation."
我不想要这个婴儿床
I don't want this crib.
嘿，爸
Hey, Dad.
- 你过的好吗？  - 嗯
- Have a good day? - Yeah.
繫上安全带
Seat belt, please.
- 文替珊蒂洗了多久的衣服？  - 喔，老天，每个星期连续八年
- How long has Vin been doin' Sandy's laundry? - Oh, geez, every week for 8 years.
- 这真的很久  - 的确很久
- That's a long time. - It IS a long time.
他是个老人，文
He's a good guy... Vin.
- 我不在文身边的时候是什麽样子？  - 他不喜欢人，大家也不喜欢他
- What's Vin like when I'm not around? - He don't like people, people don't like him.
除了猫跟你之外，你为什麽喜欢他？
Except cat and you. Why you like him?
喔，这可真直接
Oh, it'll be straight.
奥利佛，快点
Oliver, come on!
早餐好了喔，快要冷了
Breakfast is ready! Gonna get cold!
走吧
Let's go!
- 海，妈  - 不要这麽惊讶，坐下吧
- Hi, Mom. - Don't look so surprised, sit down.
你的大日子要吃好一点，坐啊
Need some fuel for your big day, right? Sit.
- 都是你做的吗？  - 嗯，都是我做的，我知道怎麽做菜
- You made all this? - Yes, I made it all, I know how to cook.
- 我今天放假  - 谢谢
- I took the day off. - Thanks.
不客气，小家伙
You're welcome, Bub.
你不会吗？我来教你
Did you have any trouble? Come here, I'll show you the trick.
你要先把领子立起来
You gotta pop this up.
好的
Okay.
- 神奇的事发生了  - 我爱你，妈
- Now that's magic. - I love you, Mom.
我也是
Me, too.
坐下，你要咖啡还是果汁
Sit down, okay, coffee or juice?
- 拿铁  - 很敢挑嘛
- Latte. - Nice try.
- 我的羊水破了  - 叫水管工
- My water is broken! - Call a plumber.
快走啊，起床
Let's go! Get up!
各位好，坐下吧，孩子们，谢谢
Hello... sit down children, thank you.
早安，欢迎参加圣派翠克小学的「我们身边的圣人」发表会
Good morning, welcome to Are Saints Among Us assembly at St. Patrick.
小朋友们都非常努力
And the children have been working very hard.
看到他们选择谁是圣人应该很有趣
And it'll be interesting to see which parents they have chosen as saints.
我想你们应该都很紧张
I'm sure you're all very nervous.
我们第一位发表者是琪夏
Our first speaker is Keesha Demorsey.
真实圣人，我选择泰瑞莎修女
For my real-life saint, I picked Mother Teresa of Calcutta.
- 这....这，  - 好吧，好吧
- This... it's... - Okay, okay.
先停下，先停
Stop anywhere, anywhere.
你什麽时候才会像个男人一样
When will you become like man?
老天，我的尊严
Jesus, my manhood!
圣尼可拉斯，各位鼓掌
St. Nicolas of Sunny Side, everybody.
好了，下一位发表的是奥利佛伯朗，奥利佛伯朗
All right, next up we have Oliver Bronstein... Oliver Bronstein.
「圣人就是牺牲并致力奉献于其他人的人」
"Saints are human beings we celebrate for their commitment and dedication to other human beings."
引用自杰拉蒂老师，三月左右
Brother Geraghty, circa, around March.
- 这裡不是医院  - 现在你又变成火箭医生了吗
- This isn't the hospital. - So, now you're a rocket surgeon.
快点，进去吧
Come on, get inside.
现代的圣人，我选择的人如同圣威廉罗彻斯特拥有许多价值
For my modern-day saint I chose a man who shares many of the same qualities as St. William of Rochester.
从表面上来看，也许有人会认为我选择的圣人是最不像圣人的人
On the surface, one might think my saint is the least likely candidate for sainthood.
他也不是很开心的人
He's not a happy person.
他不喜欢其他人而其他人也不喜欢他
He doesn't like people and not many people like him.
他脾气暴躁，易怒，愤世嫉俗，我敢肯定他充满遗憾。
He's grumpy, he's angry, he's mad at the world, I'm sure full of regrets.
他喝太多酒，抽淤，赌博，诅咒别人，说谎和欺骗
He drinks too much, he smokes, he gambles, curses, lies and cheats.
而且花许多时间与夜晚的淑女在一起
And he spends a lot of time with the Lady of the Night.
这是你们对他的第一印象
That's what you see at first glance.
如果你们深入了解，不管他的过错
If you dig deeper you see a man beyond his faults.
文森特麦肯纳先生出生于1946年
Mr. Vincent McKenna was born in 1946
羊头湾，是第一代的爱尔兰移民之子
in Sheepshead Bay the son of first generation Irish immigrants.
在布鲁克林街头出身贫困
Growing up poor on the streets of Brooklyn,
文森特学会了许多小孩子不该知道的事
Vincent learned all the things that kids shouldn't need to know:
打架，诅咒以及赌博
Fighting, cursing and gambling.
1965年，身为美军第五军团的成员
In 1965, as a member of the United States Army 5th Regiment,
文森特与其他450名军人投身德浪河谷
Vincent was among the four hundred and fifty soldiers dropped into La Drang Valley
并受到2000位敌军的攻击
and immediately ambushed by 2000 enemy troops.
那时他英勇地拯救了两名受伤的军官
There he heroically saved the lives of two wounded officers pinned down by enemy fire.
并带他们脱离险境
And carried them to safety.
之后他被授予青铜星奖励其勇敢行为
Has was awarded the bronze star for his bravery.
我想跟你们解释文森特麦肯纳先生的最好方式就是
I imagine the best way to tell you who Mr. Vincent McKenna is
跟你们解释他为我做了什麽
is to tell you what he's done for me.
我跟我妈刚搬到这裡时，我们不认识任何人
When me and my mom first moved here, we knew no one.
而麦肯纳先生接纳我
And Mr. McKenna took me in.
他本来不需要，而正确来说，不想要...
When he didn't have to, and most likely, didn't want to...
但他还是做了，因为这是圣人会做的事
but he did it anyhow, 'cause THAT'S what saints do.
我们造访了他结缡四十年的妻子，珊蒂，最近刚过世
We visited his wife, Sandy, of 40 years, who recently passed away.
文在过去八年内，每个星期都替她洗衣服，即使她已经不记得文
Vin's done her laundry EVERY week for the past 8 years, long after she no longer recognized him.
因为圣人永不放弃
Because saints never give up.
他教我怎麽对抗，如何坚定立场以及勇敢，如何大声说话与有魄力
He taught me how to fight, how to stand my ground and be brave, how to speak up and be bold.
因为圣人会替自己与他人对抗，因此声音才会被听到
Because saints fight for themselves and others, so that they might be heard.
他教我怎麽赌博，赛马，玩乐透
He taught me how to gamble, horse racing, Keno,
还有其他，所以我会被禁足到18岁
the Over and Under, which is a big reason why I'm grounded 'til I'm eighteen.
但我学到风险以及孤注一掷
But in that I learned how to take risks and go for broke.
因为人生的赔率会对你不利
Because in life the odds can be stacked against you.
这是文森的猫，菲力，牠吃高级猫粮而文森吃沙丁鱼罐头
This is Vin's cat, Felix, who eats gourmet cat food while Vin eats sardines.
因为圣人勇于牺牲
'Cause saints make sacrifices.
没错，文森特麦肯纳先生有缺陷，严重缺陷
Yes, Mr. Vincent McKenna is flawed, seriously flawed,
但就跟我们曾经学过的其他圣人一样
But just like the all the other saints we studied,
因为结果，圣人也是凡人，非常凡人
because, after all, saints are human beings... very human beings.
勇气，牺牲，怜悯，人性
Courage, sacrifice, compassion, humanity.
这些造就了圣人
These are the markings of a saint
这也是让文森特麦肯纳先生成为圣人文森特麦肯纳先生的原因
and what makes Mr. Vincent McKenna not so far removed from St. William of Rochester.
因此，我要介绍我的朋友与保母
And with that, I'd like to present my friend and babysitter,
文森特麦肯纳先生，是羊头湾的圣文森特
Mr. Vincent McKenna, for sainthood, and hereby proclaim him St. Vincent of Sheepshead Bay.
- 谢谢你，先生  - 谢谢你，孩子
- Thank you, Sir. - Thank you, kid.
羊头湾的圣文森特
St. Vincent from Sheepshead Bay.
等等，我知道了，我欠你钱，你想要什麽
Wait, I got it, I owe you money anyhow. What are you lookin' at?
- 硬椒盐脆饼  - 我也想要
- Hard Pretzels. - That's just what I was lookin' at.
如果你在正确时机，用力敲....就会掉下两个
If you hit it just right, you end up with... TWO for the price of one.
- 很厉害吧  - 的确很厉害，小鬼
- Pretty cool. - That's pretty good, kiddo.
- 我也许应该学一下  - 麦肯纳先生，时间差不多了
- I might have to adopt that. - Mr. McKenna, it's about that time.
好吧，拿去，不过严格来说你还是偷东西
All right, hold your horses. Though, technically, that's stealing.
不要哭，没事...
You don't cry, it's okay...
所以是？黑人？白人？丑人？
So, what is it? Black? White? Ugly?
我喜欢这小孩
I like this baby.
- 你喜欢这小孩？  - 嗯，到目前为止
- You like this baby? - Yeah... so far.
我太开心了
I'm... I'm so happy.
你知道这是很特别的礼物，我可以教你
You know it's a special present, yeah? I'll teach you.
这不是俄国的，但...抱歉，小猫
It is not Russian, but... Sorry, cat!
- 你一定得吃蔬菜  - 色彩很丰富，我得说
- You must eat vegetables. - It's colorful, I'll say that.
- 我喜欢绿豆  - 你喜欢？
- I like the green beans. - You do?
嗯，我觉得你的义大利麵跟绿豆不太够
Yeah, I don't think you ever get enough spaghetti and green beans.
- 我妈可以吃完一整罐  - 所以你脑袋才会变这样
- My Mom eats 'em out of a can. - That's how your brain got stilted.
- 喔，你的脑袋有问题  - 这不太好
- Oh, you have stilted brain. - That's probably good.
- 就像智障  - 嘿，智开头的词不好听
- Like the retard - Hey, the "r" word's not cool.
- 这很不政治正确  - 怎麽说？
- It's not politically correct. - Why is this?
- 除非你说侏儒  - 侏儒？
- Except when you say "midget". - Midget?
为什麽侏儒不行？
Why not midget?
这些食物可以打击飢饿...
This food beats hunger...
有头髮的话
by a hair.
- 你不想要说些什麽吗？  - 像什麽？
- Don't you want to say somethin'? - Like what?
像是祷告或是祝福
Like a blessing or a prayer.
嗯，我想不用了
Naw, I better not.
小婴儿在哭了
The baby is crying tears.
你的衣服都湿了
You... in wet clothes.
给你，大家都在吃饭就你没有对吗？
There, everyone has been fed except you, huh?
喔，这裡有点冷
Oh, it's chill... it's a bit chilly in here.
一人字幕组  2014.12.12 pm2:57